His story will make you cry. His music will make you
sing. His triumph will make you cheer.
The Jazz Singer is a drama, music, romance film directed by Richard Fleischer.
A young Jewish man is torn between tradition and individuality when his
old-fashioned family objects to his career as a jazz singer.
Jess Robin / Yussel Rabinovitch, played by Neil Diamond.
Cantor Rabinovitch, played by Laurence Olivier.
Molly Bell, played by Lucie Arnaz.
Rivka Rabinovitch, played by Catlin Adams.
Bubba, played by Franklyn Ajaye.
Keith Lennox, played by Paul Nicholas.
The Jazz Singer is a 1980 American musical drama film directed by
Richard Fleischer and produced by Jerry Leider.
The film stars Neil Diamond (in his acting debut), Laurence Olivier and Lucie Arnaz, and tells the story
of a young singer who is torn between tradition and pursuing his dreams as a pop singer.
Based on the 1925 play of the same title by Samson Raphaelson, it is the fourth film adaptation,
following the 1927 and the 1952 theatrical adaptions, and a 1959 television adaptation.
Developed as a starring vehicle for Diamond, who had undergone a revival of popularity in the late
1970s, the film was intended to be produced by Paramount and AFD, with Sidney J.
Furie directing, and Deborah Raffin acting opposite Diamond.
However, production was plagued with several delays in filming, the
departures of Furie and Raffin, and numerous script rewrites.
The Jazz Singer was released by AFD on December 19, 1980, and was a critical and commercial disappointment,
although it did make a substantial profit, doubling its $13 million budget by making $27.1 million.
Critics panned the acting of Diamond and Olivier, while praising Arnaz's performance,
the accompanying soundtrack and live musical performances in the film.
The soundtrack eventually reached multi-platinum status, becoming Diamond's most successful
album to date and one of the more successful film soundtrack albums in history.
The tone is emotional.